GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
Where is Xander Wilde?
My God.
There's two of them.
I'm gonna drive
you mad, brother.
All of Gotham will
be joining you, too.
You shall become
the Demon's Head.
She's got the mark
of the Demon's Head.
No woman has ever been allowed
to lead the League of Shadows.
The sisters of the League
are yours to command.
Tell me what I need to know.
(GROANING)
BRUCE: I could have
killed Jerome, and I didn't.
Don't take so much responsibility
that you get yourself killed.
JEROME: I came up with a plan
to turn this city into a madhouse.
Oh, we're gonna
need a lot more of this!
Thank you all for
coming this evening.
As your interim mayor,
I know my recent
appointment was sudden,
and perhaps a bit
of a shock to some.
Quite frankly, I was shocked.
What is important now is
the future of this great city.
That is why I'm
meeting with all of you.
Well, Mayor, as chairperson of
Gotham's Moral Authority Society,
our members have been,
quite frankly, unnerved
by the recent going-ons
in our great city.
We have seen
criminals take office,
gunfights in our
streets, corruption...
Mrs. Haverstock.
The Commissioner and I have
worked tirelessly these past few weeks
to improve the way
this city conducts itself.
Wyatt, everything all right?
We're looking into it now, sir.
Did a window blow open?
It's gotten so cold.
(BOTH LADIES GASP)
- What's happened?
- MAN: Don't come any closer.
No!
(SHUDDERING)
(SCREAMING)
Good evening, everyone.
(GASPING)
What do you want with us?
Sorry, no time for
questions, Mr. Mayor.
You see, your presence is
urgently needed elsewhere.
Whatever you expect
as ransom, I will double it.
I have access to the
police pension fund.
Wow, that could
be a lot of money.
Tempting, but no thanks.
Bridgit, isn't it?
I can get you safe
passage from the city,
money, a new home...
It was people like you that
locked me up in Strange's lab,
and thanks to that, there
is no Bridgit anymore.
I can get you a pardon, son.
All will be forgiven.
Just stop this lunatic.
Lunatic's a little harsh.
I prefer "visionary."
Oswald, can't you do something?
Afraid not.
I am with Mr. Valeska 100%.
Every cop in this city
will be looking for us,
and when they find you,
expect no mercy,
just a hail of bullets.
So serious.
That's why your approval
ratings are so low.
Hey, tell you what.
Try threatening me again,
but this time, try it with a smile.
Oh! See, this is what's wrong.
Nobody knows how to
have fun anymore, right?
But see our friend
down there, bag head?
He's figured out a
way to solve that.
(STUTTERING AND SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
It's time to give this
city the boost it needs.
Time to stop taking
ourselves so seriously.
I mean, come on, Gotham,
what do you have to lose?
Except your sanity.
(BOTH LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
You gonna tell me why we needed
to come to the garage, Alfred?
Happy birthday, Master Wayne.
You remembered.
Of course I remembered.
I bloody love your birthdays.
Your seventh was
an absolute blinder.
Yeah, I remember you had
about 50 kids come up here,
but you were off
outside on your own.
You were obsessed by this
one gift that your dad gave you,
this bright red wagon.
You were in the garden all
day, collecting all these rocks.
When I asked you, "What are
you gonna do with these rocks?"
You said, "I'm gonna
build a home for my wagon.
"A secret place that
only I know about."
What's this?
Well, it's the reason why I brought
you down to the garage, Master Bruce.
(CAR STARTING)
Alfred, I don't
know what to say.
V8, five-liter,
460-horsepower engine.
Painted matte
black, anti-reflective,
very difficult to see at night.
Oh, and of course this...
100% bulletproof.
Best be prepared, eh?
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, mate.
HARVEY: Jim, hey, what gives?
The mayor and the police commissioner
have been kidnapped by Jerome.
Got every cop in the city out
there searching all the spots
Jerome has been
seen the last week.
You got something for me?
I was gonna say I just won
100 bucks in the scratch-off lotto
at the liquor store, and we
could go to the track with it,
but you can do your thing first.
- Gordon.
- PENGUIN: We need to talk.
- Oswald?
- I'm out back. Come alone.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
GORDON: All right.
Well, this is a first.
Are you doing
anything about Jerome?
We're looking for him.
Do you know where he is?
And if I did, do you really
think I would just tell you?
Have you march in
there, guns blazing?
He needs to be stopped.
He has everyone under his thumb.
Freeze, Firefly, Hatter.
They are all part of his
plan. A dark, terrible plan.
Which is?
Scarecrow has
made a gas for him.
- Like the fear toxin?
- Worse.
Much worse.
I saw it turn someone into a
maniacal, cackling, violent animal.
What does he plan to do with it?
He's smart. He hasn't shared
the details of his plans with anyone.
Instead, we all have a
separate task to perform.
Such as?
He has yet to give me my role.
Why did you come here if
you're not gonna help me?
He scares the living
hell out of me, okay?
I mean, I was willing to play
along with him for a while.
Perhaps he had a
way to make us all rich,
or return to the good
old days, you know.
But nothing good
will come of this.
Or maybe you just
don't like the competition.
Jerome casts quite the shadow.
Oh, please.
He's a maniac. An anarchist.
He is not interested
in money or power.
And I am an
honest criminal, Jim.
Where is he? Where is the gas?
He only tells you
what he needs to,
when he needs to.
I just know he
has to be stopped.
HARVEY: Jim, hey!
You down here?
- Jim?
- Yup.
Hey, a uni just spotted
Jerome near Paisley Square.
All right, let's go.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SINGING "TIME HAS COME TODAY")
Hey, what's happening to my mic?
Hey, buddy, beat it, will
you? I'm trying to work here.
Whoo!
- (SINGER GRUNTS)
- (CROWD GASPS)
Where's everyone going?
(CROWD SCREAMING)
Ladies and gentlemen, we
are the Arkham Asylum Lunatics,
and we came here
to blow some minds!
Sorry to interrupt
your little show.
But you are gonna
love this next one.
Introducing Mayor Pritchard,
Commissioner Reynolds,
Archbishop McGregor,
and this lady.
Whoever she is.
This is everybody.
Everybody, say hi.
Now, as you can see,
we're still waiting for
two guests of honor.
But in the meantime,
let's go over the rules of
tonight's entertainment, shall we?
Dynamite.
Trigger.
I don't get what I want,
boom.
Headless people.
And if any of you are
thinking of going anywhere,
you'll die, too.
Now, the one man who
can get me what I want.
Calling Gordon.
Calling Captain James Gordon.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
I speak on behalf of myself
and all other gang
leaders in this city
when I say your
arrogance and disrespect
will no longer be tolerated.
You beat and then dragged
my brother from here
like a dog.
Your brother's an ass.
He abuses our staff and
refuses to pay his exorbitant tab.
He is my brother,
and he demands your respect.
And I suppose an apology
would be out of the question.
(CHUCKLES)
Your blood will be his apology.
Thought so.
(MEN GRUNTING)
I could have handled them.
That's the advantage of having
your own personal army, Tabs.
You don't have to.
Isn't that right?
What's wrong?
Ra's al Ghul chose you,
no one else, to
pass on his spirit.
We will serve you,
protect you, of course,
but surely you intend
to continue his legacy,
and not just remain
here in this place.
What does that mean?
"Continue his legacy."
I like the sound of that.
As I told you,
we have much more to show you.
Are you ready?
Yes.
GUARD: What the hell was that?
(TIMER BEEPING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Gentlemen, ladies,
your assistance is
urgently required.
Be careful, these are
very dangerous materials.
We're counting on it.
More laughing gas,
we need to make.
There's no time to waste.
We need it in bulk, you see.
Well... Well, how
much of it do you need?
Oh!
CRANE: This much.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
JEROME: Ladies and
gentlemen, as I live and breathe,
James Gordon is in the house.
I'm not talking to you
until I can get up there
and check on the
well-being of your hostages.
JEROME: First of
all, Jim, you're late.
Secondly, I think I'm the one
who should be making demands.
Don't you?
What you're doing is
an act of terror, Valeska.
Ask our mayor what
this city's policy is
on negotiating with terrorists.
"Terrorists"?
Frankly, I'm
offended. No, no, no.
That's close enough, Gordon.
(CROWD SCREAMING)
JEROME: And none of
you go anywhere, either.
Dead man's trigger.
This falls out of my hand
for any reason, and... Bang!
(CROWD GASPS)
I got two empty chairs here.
You haven't even asked
me who they're for yet.
All right. I'll bite.
Who are they for?
Come on, James.
You're a detective.
Do some detecting.
Jeremiah, your brother.
Bingo. That's one.
And the other?
Well, the only other
irksome do-gooder
who's ever spoiled
my fun in this town.
Bruce Wayne.
No.
No?
You can take me.
I'll sit up there with one of
those things around my neck,
but I won't let you have him.
Oh, I don't want you, Jim.
I want my brother,
and I want Bruce.
I want them now.
All right, let me get these people
out of here, I'll come up there...
You are not listening to me.
And that is forcing my hand.
Jerome.
- (DETONATOR BUZZING)
- No!
(CROWD SCREAMING)
JEROME: Bring me my brother.
Bring me Wayne.
Bring them now.
(ALFRED SINGING
"HAPPY BIRTHDAY")
I'll get some plates.
You know, for a billionaire,
your security system is lame.
Miss Kyle.
BRUCE: Thank you, Alfred.
Enjoy.
Thank you.
For what?
Visiting me on my birthday.
Oh!
I actually didn't know
it was your birthday,
I just happened to be
strolling in the neighborhood.
Either way, it's
good to see you.
I knew it was an act.
What?
The brat,
and the drinking, the friends.
It was an act.
I think you're more
sure about that than me.
Master Bruce,
we have visitors.
Bruce, we need your help.
BRUCE: What happened?
Don't you know it's rude
to keep a guy waiting?
Bring me my hostages, James.
My trigger finger
is getting itchy.
The hostages he wants
are his brother and you.
What, you're having a
laugh. No bloody way.
I don't like it any
more than you do,
but, Bruce, you
have to trust me.
Lucius and I have a plan.
JEROME: You know what?
I don't think you're taking
me seriously enough.
Well, all right.
Let's see.
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
Eenie, meeny, miny, mo.
One of these
people got to... Go.
Oh, it's that guy.
Oh, well.
Did you see what just happened?
That man's a raving bloody
lunatic. He can't be trusted.
For once, I agree with Alfred.
Bruce, listen to me.
With your help, we can
prevent more deaths.
What's the plan?
Jerome is using a
short-wave radio trigger
with a dead man's switch.
If we can cut the signal,
he won't be able to
activate the explosives.
This emits a powerful signal
that disables all
radio waves close to it.
Once within a few
feet of Jerome's device,
his trigger will be useless.
It will give us the
time for the snipers
to get a clean shot on
Jerome, Firefly, and the others.
If I wear this, then that gives
you time to take them out?
Correct.
Are you sure it's gonna work?
I'm positive.
99% positive.
What are we waiting for?
Those people need our help.
Good man.
LELIA: Ra's owned this house
for as long as the city has existed.
He said he kept
his secrets in here.
Ancient secrets.
None of us have ever
seen what's behind this door.
It remains locked.
And there is no key.
Tried dynamite?
No need.
Our master chose
you for a reason.
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
BARBARA: All my life,
I have known that I
was meant for more,
that there was something deep
inside of me that I couldn't explain.
I'm home.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
SNIPER: Sir, we
got target in sight.
No way in from below the stage.
Four of my men
have found positions.
Good. Stay low, hang tight.
No hair triggers.
One missed shot
means adiós Mayor.
SNIPER: Copy that.
Standing by.
I watched the news. I know
why you're here, Mr. Gordon.
And you must be out of your mind
if you think I'm gonna be
led like a lamb to slaughter.
I understand your concern,
but your brother doesn't bluff.
If we ignore his demands,
there's no telling what he might do.
We can block his
remote signal with this.
If you and Bruce can get
within a few feet of him,
it will disable his remote.
He'll be a sitting duck.
Our snipers can
take it from there.
JEREMIAH: For
God's sake, Gordon.
You have to know what he wants.
To murder us both
on live television.
BRUCE: Mr. Valeska.
I'm Bruce Wayne.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Likewise.
I wish the circumstances
were better.
May I ask what it is
you've been working on?
Yeah, it's a compact electrical
engine. It generates power.
Fascinating. How much power?
Just two could light up every
building south of Westford Bridge.
You have a brilliant mind.
And we all hope we can
soon be rid of your brother,
so that you can carry out
your work free from fear.
I understand if you
choose not to help us today,
but I trust that Captain
Gordon and Mr. Fox
will see that no
harm comes to me.
But, even if it does,
maybe by facing Jerome
I can show the people of
Gotham that standing up to terror
is the only way to
take its power away.
JEREMIAH: Well said.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Harvey.
- Hey.
Just got word that
Freeze and Scarecrow
broke into Wayne
Industries' chemical lab.
Jerome's playing
the long game here,
but we're not gonna be sure what
it is unless we get ahead of him.
The gas.
Penguin told me about
a new Scarecrow toxin.
Head over to the lab. We're
on our way to the square.
They've got a weapon.
Poison gas.
Okay, let's go.
Thank you.
You two.
(MAN LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Hey. Hey, buddy.
What happened?
What's so funny?
No, no, no, don't.
Ma'am, let me help you.
What happened?
They made us
make it. Tons of it.
Where is it?
It's gone. They took it.
(JEROME SINGING)
Well, look who
decided to show up.
We were starting to get nervous,
especially the mayor here.
My guest of honor.
Please, take your
seats on stage.
Come on.
Don't be shy.
It's all right.
JEROME: We don't have all day.
It's activated. Just let
them get a little closer.
On my command.
SNIPER: My men
have all targets in view.
Standing by.
Hi, brother.
Now.
Fire. All targets, fire.
(CROWD SCREAMING)
I had my guys take up the
best vantage points last night.
So they've been watching
your little SWAT team all day.
Now, Bruce, brother dear.
Get up on stage.
Time to get this party
really started, huh?
What are you doing here?
This is a restricted area.
Our cargo is too
precious to waste.
Let me give you something
I like to keep up my sleeves
for times just like these.
(GASPING AND SCREAMING)
Oh, my God!
You can pilot this
contraption alone, sir?
Yes.
Then look into my eyes.
(WATCH TICKING)
The kidnappings.
The concert in the square.
All to draw the biggest crowd,
so we can drop the
laughing gas on them.
This is madness.
I thought you'd appreciate
the beauty of it all.
But Jerome was right.
You know he
anticipated your betrayal?
That's right.
You went to Gordon.
Judas.
Tie him up.
Put him on the blimp.
Jerome wants him to
have a bird's-eye view.
This book tracks Ra's' legacy
dating back nine centuries.
Did you know he not only
overthrew governments,
but infiltrated royal families?
Ra's influenced history.
He was a cult leader.
And he still has
them brainwashed.
And what about me,
am I brainwashed?
There are things written here
that could change the way
we view the past forever.
Perhaps I'm the one to
bring that change to light.
Look.
This book was compiled
by shamans and mystics
from all over Eastern
Asia and the Middle East.
(SCOFFS) "Shamans and
mystics." Give me a break.
It contains formulas for
potions and incantations
set to raise demons.
To curse our enemies
and contact the dead.
This isn't you.
The Barbara I know would
have already sold all of this junk
- to the highest bidder.
- "Junk"?
This is my destiny.
And being with me and
Selina at the club, that isn't?
You begged me
to partner with you.
Can't you see who
that is up there?
That is me and
Ra's 400 years ago.
Oh, please.
- That doesn't even look like you.
- It looks exactly like me.
It is me.
I have finally found
my true purpose.
I'm not gonna let your
jealousy distract me.
Ladies, escort Ms.
Galavan to the street.
I'll show myself out.
Actually, I think it's
time my loyal servants
taught you some manners.
Why don't you do it?
Because I am the one true heir
of an immortal god's
ancient dynasty.
And I don't dirty my fingers
with the likes of you anymore.
JEROME: No parent will admit it.
But everyone's
got their favorites.
Right, brother?
The one who cleans their room,
does their homework,
doesn't try to kill everybody.
Little Mr. Perfect here.
Yeah, he was that guy.
He got adopted by rich folks.
He went to the top
schools, then a top college.
Meanwhile, I got
dragged to the circus
by my depressed,
alcoholic mother.
Forced to clean up
elephant dung every day.
MAN: Who cares?
Do you know how big
those things are, folks?
But I know something
that Mommy and Daddy,
they never knew.
You're as crazy as I am.
- No.
- (CROWD MURMURING)
It's in your DNA.
See,
we got the same blood
running through us.
We are practically identical.
You are a killer.
It's your nature.
Stop trying to fight it.
Take your best shot.
(ROARS)
Hey, what the hell happened?
Snipers are dead.
Get up on the roof,
take as many as you can.
All right, just know a bunch of
chemicals are heading this way.
Scarecrow had the
Wayne chemists mix it up.
That's why he's been stalling.
He wants a big crowd.
He's gonna release the
laughing gas right here.
We need to evacuate the area.
Get these people out of here.
Do whatever you have
to. Get them out of here.
Time to kill this
maniac once and for all.
(CROWD GASPING)
JEROME: That was
so good! I love you.
- (GUN COCKING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
(BUTTON CLICKS)
(STATIC BUZZ)
(GRUNTS)
- (CROWD SCREAMING)
- (LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
WOMAN: Hey, hey!
Look! Up in the sky!
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Holy crap.
Excuse me, sir.
Could you help me?
No can do, sport.
Gotta get this rig into
position for the boss.
And where is that?
Paisley Square.
Almost there.
Then I can drop the load
with this lever.
You turn this thing
around right now!
Can you not see that...
Like I said, pal,
no can do.
(CROWD SCREAMING)
JEROME: It's coming.
Get into position.
HARVEY: Holy moly.
Holy moly.
Jim, are you seeing this?
Yeah, get everyone out of here.
I'm going after Jerome.
I can take it down with a shot.
And risk spilling the chemicals?
Oh, yeah, right.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oswald?
Jim! Jim, help me.
They knocked me out,
and now I am in some blimp
with that horrible gas.
And the pilot, he's
been hypnotized.
(STUTTERING)
You're on the blimp?
Yes. Yes, you have to help me.
No, you're gonna help us.
You're near the river.
I need you to
steer it over there.
Steer a blimp?
Are you out of your mind, Jim?
I don't even drive my own car.
If you don't, thousands
will die. Maybe worse.
What's worse than that?
How can you run an empire
in a city full of lunatics?
Hands up.
Beautiful, isn't she?
(BLIMP HOVERING)
Just give me a second.
Gotta call Tyler, tell
him he's in position.
(GROANS)
Yes?
- Not cool.
- TYLER: Jerome?
Jerome?
I'm in position...
(CHUCKLING) Doesn't matter.
Too late anyway.
Bombs away!
(GASPING)
Funny.
No!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
PENGUIN: Come on.
Now, come on.
Up! Up! Up!
Oh, okay. All right.
Okay, okay. Okay...
River. River...
Where is the river?
Quite the dilemma, Jim.
Are you gonna let
me fall and die...
(GROANING)
Or are you gonna pull
me up and arrest me?
What's it gonna be?
A lawman or a murderer?
(GRUNTING)
Good old Gordon.
Always playing by the rules.
That's why I'll outlive you.
That's why I'm loved,
'cause I don't give a
damn about the rules.
It's a long way down.
You sure you'll outlive me?
Oh, I'm sure.
'Cause I'm more than a man.
I'm an idea, a philosophy.
And I will live on
in the shadows,
within Gotham's discontent.
You'll be seeing me soon.
Au revoir.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(THUDDING)
WOMAN: Never
thought I'd see this.
MAN: Sure he's
dead. I can't believe.
Is he?
Yeah.
GORDON: Get back.
GCPD. Everybody get back.
Mr. Valeska.
I meant what I said about your
work being of importance to the city.
Let Wayne Enterprises
fund your work with a grant.
Thank you.
Captain.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oswald.
Um...
Hello.
Still here.
Will someone please get
me the hell off this thing?
We're on it.
How do we get a blimp
down safely from over a river?
You asking me?
I say we let him stew up
there for a few more hours.
We'll get a hold
of the standby pilot.
Have him advise.
Sit tight, all right?
Oh!
And Oswald Cobblepot,
Gotham thanks you.
Wait, Jim. Jim?
Jim? Jim.
Jim!
(TABITHA GRUNTING)
Never touch me again.
Ms. Kean has a
new path to take now.
- It no longer involves you.
- Is that so?
We will accept you leaving
this city and never coming back.
The only thing I'll accept
is you kissing my ass.
We have been trained
by the League of Shadows
in 90 different forms of combat
since we were five years old.
Oh, yeah? Which one of
you bitches wants to go first?
(GRUNTING)
Next time, we kill you.
Let me help you.
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Who the hell are you guys?
The ones that have been
watching you and Barbara Kean,
the impostor, for
quite some time.
We serve the one
and only true master,
Ra's al Ghul.
But he's dead.
Death is only an illusion.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(COUGHING)
JEROME: Hello, brother.
Didn't think you can get
rid of me so easily, did you?
See, my days were
numbered, but you...
Oh, you can continue on for me.
Be my ultimate revenge.
So, calm yourself.
Don't fight it.
Breathe it in.
This gas was a special
mixture I had made
just for you.
Something to
finally set you free.
- It's time to have some fun.
- (LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Burn it down, brother.
Burn it all down.
English - SDH